<?xml version="1.0"?>
<coursepage title="Interfaces Summary">
  <css>
   dt {
      margin-top: 1em;
   }
  </css>
  <title>Interfaces (Summary)</title>
  <subtitle> </subtitle>
  <preface>
    <![CDATA[
    ]]>
  </preface>
  <video ytid="XXXXXXXX"/>
  <epilogue>
    <![CDATA[
    ]]>
  </epilogue>
  <exercises>
    <exercise>
    <![CDATA[
       Look at the libraries for one of your favourite programming languages
       and try to find implemenations of List, USet, and SSet interfaces.
       The exact names maybe different, but most languages and libraries
       implement these interfaces.<p>
       Here are some of the languages we know about:
       <dl>
         <dt><a class="button" href="nojavascript.html"
         onclick="document.getElementById('cpp').className='';return false">C++</a></dt> 
         <dd id="cpp" class="hidden">In the C++ Standard Template
         Library, there are several implementations of the List
         interface, including <code>vector</code>, <code>list</code>,
         and <code>slist</code>. The USet interface is implemented
         by the <code>hash_set</code> class and the SSet interface is
         implemented by the <code>hash_set</code> class.
         <p>
         The STL also includes the <code>map</code> and
         <code>hash_map</code> implementations of the Map interface as
         well as restricted lists, including the <code>queue</code>,
         <code>stack</code>, and <code>deque</code>.
         <dd>

         <dt><a class="button" href="nojavascript.html"
         onclick="document.getElementById('python').className='';return false">Python</a></dt> 
         <dd id="python" class="hidden">In the standard Python libraries,
         the List interface is implemented by the <code>list</code> class,
         the USet interface is implemented by the <code>set</code> class,
         and the Map interface is implemented by the <code>dict</code> class.
         The standard Python library does not include any implementation
         of the SSet interface, though the third-party <code>sortedcontainers</code> library provides a <code>SortedSet</code> class.

         <dt><a class="button" href="nojavascript.html"
         onclick="document.getElementById('java').className='';return false">Java</a></dt> 
         <dd id="java" class="hidden">In Java, the List interface is
         implemented
         by the <code>Vector</code>, <code>ArrayList</code>, and
         <code>LinkedList</code> classes, among others.  The Uset
         interface is called the <code>Set</code> interface and is
         implemented by the <code>HashSet</code> class.  The SSet
         interface is called the <code>SortedSet</code> interface and
         is implemented by the <code>TreeSet</code> class.
         <p>
         Java also has the <code>Map</code> interface that is implemented
         by the <code>HashMap</code> and <code>SortedMap</code>
         classes.  The Java SDK also contains the <code>Stack</code>
         and <code>ArrayDeque</code> classes that implement the Stack
         and Deque interfaces.
         <dd>
       </dl>
       <p>
       How about other languages like PHP, JavaScript, Perl, Ruby, Objective-C,
       C#, Swift, or Perl?
       </p>
    ]]>
    </exercise>
    <exercise>
    <![CDATA[
       Do as many as you can of Exercises <a target="_blank" href="http://opendatastructures.org/ods-java/1_8_Discussion_Exercises.html">1.1&ndash;1.7</a> in the textbook.  Use any programming language you like. (Note: For most of these exercises it helps if you've done the previous exercise for hte programming language you've chosen.)
    ]]>
    </exercise>
  </exercises>
  <js-head>
    <![CDATA[
    ]]>
  </js-head>
  <js-tail>
   <![CDATA[
    function someJSInTailSection() {
    }
   ]]>
  </js-tail>
</coursepage>
